<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alto:alto xmlns:alto="http://www.loc.gov/standards/alto/ns-v4#">
  <alto:Layout>
    <alto:Page ID="page_9">
      <alto:TextBlock>
        <alto:String>Their hard work paid off in the 62nd minute. Lily Bryant lofted the ball to a running Tordin on the left side of the field. Tordin was flanked by two Dartmouth defenders — but that didn’t stop her. Tordin flicked the ball to the blind side of her defenders, taking the ball off the half volley over the head of Hardy and into the top of the net. This marked Tordin’s sixth goal in six games. Despite being up 3–0, Princeton did not let up focus, determined to net their strongest performance for the senior celebration game. In the 65th minute, MacNab sent a curling cross to the back post, perfectly placed to the head of a wide-open first-year midfielder Brooks Dawahare for Dawahare’s fourth goal of the season and Princeton’s fourth goal of the game. The Tigers finished out the game strong, clinching the 4–0 win over Dartmouth and a victory for the Tigers’ senior night. Princeton looks to build on this momentum next Saturday on the road at Columbia (7–3–4, 5–0–1) for the regular season finale, a game that determines home field advantage in the postseason Ivy Tournament. It’s simple: A win next week at Columbia would seal the number one seed in Ivy play for the Tigers. “We just have to be us next week,” Driscoll said. “We just want to be ourselves and play the way we’re capable of playing in terms of being on the front foot and being aggressive. When we do that, we’re really good.” “Columbia is a great team, but I think when we come together as a team and we play our game, we’re honestly unstoppable,” Barry concluded.  Leila Eshaghpour-Silberman is a Sports contributor and contributing Features writer for the ‘Prince.’ Naomi Segel is a Sports contributor for the ‘Prince.’ Please direct any corrections requests to corrections[at]dailyprincetonian.com.  3/21/25, 6:20 PM   Women’s soccer downs Dartmouth 4–0 on senior day - The Princetonian  https://www.dailyprincetonian.com/article/2024/10/princeton-sports-recaps-womens-soccer-tigers-beat-dartmouth-big-green-senior-day   3/3</alto:String>
      </alto:TextBlock>
    </alto:Page>
  </alto:Layout>
</alto:alto>