<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alto:alto xmlns:alto="http://www.loc.gov/standards/alto/ns-v4#">
  <alto:Layout>
    <alto:Page ID="page_2">
      <alto:TextBlock>
        <alto:String>Maddie Feldman is a member of the Class of 2027. She intends to major in SPIA. Outside of the classroom, she DJs under the name “Disc Rocky” and recently performed at Charter Club, her first time DJing on the street. Her performance at Charter occurred after the interview was conducted. She is also a member of the Air Force ROTC. Feldman is also a contributing constructor in the Puzzles section. This interview has been lightly edited for clarity and concision.  The Daily Princetonian:   Can you tell us a little bit about yourself? How did you get into DJing?  Maddie Feldman:   I’m Maddie. I am a sophomore from D.C., and I have experienced two very strong dreams in the last year. And in fact, the first of those dreams was born exactly a year ago today. In preparation for this interview, I was looking to see at what point I was struck with DJ fever in the middle of the night. I was checking through my email receipts. I reached out to probably 15 local DJs in the area to ask how they got started, what their first programs were. I had zero musical background. I grew up playing the piano, but my twin sister is an actual piano prodigy with perfect pitch, so taking lessons after my twin sister was pretty demoralizing.  DP:   Sounds like music runs in the family.  MF:   Music definitely runs in the family. My second really strong dream ... I decided I really wanted to join the military, or at least try it out for the year. And so I’ve only ever had two dreams of this caliber, and I’ve acted accordingly.  DP:   What kind of genres and music do you like mixing?  MF:   I really do enjoy house music. DJ aficionados will likely hear that and think, oh, that’s quite the cop out, because house music is distinctive for its long intros, long outros, and pretty monotonous beat structure. It’s an easier genre to mix. That being said, it’s the genre I like the most. I’ve been getting more into the French rave vibe as well.  DP:   Do you have a dream venue on campus?  MF:   I think hitting the street will legitimize my aspiring DJ career. I was speaking with a friend when we determined that there are three learning curves to becoming a DJ. The first one is being proficient at the functions of the board, knowing the basics well enough to DJ in a dorm or the street, for that matter. The second learning curve is being comfortable enough to mix music that you haven’t listened to before, or music that you know so well that you can do better tricks with. That, I think, is worthy of DJing in venues and clubs — which honestly could be a goal of mine in the future. The third learning curve, which takes an extra 200 hours to learn, is that of an international DJ sensation. With enough practice, I could really upgrade out of my own dorm room, which is pretty much the extent to which I’ve performed.  DP:   If you could have any guest feature, who would it be?  Get the best of the ‘Prince’ delivered straight to your inbox.   Subscribe now »  3/21/25, 6:20 PM   Artist Q&amp;A: Maddie Feldman’s DJ dreams as Disc Rocky - The Princetonian  https://www.dailyprincetonian.com/article/2024/10/princeton-prospect-artist-question-and-answer-disc-rocky-dj   2/3</alto:String>
      </alto:TextBlock>
    </alto:Page>
  </alto:Layout>
</alto:alto>