<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alto:alto xmlns:alto="http://www.loc.gov/standards/alto/ns-v4#">
  <alto:Layout>
    <alto:Page ID="page_8">
      <alto:TextBlock>
        <alto:String>breakaway from junior striker Pietra Tordin in the first five minutes. The Dartmouth back line maintained strength though, staunchly diminishing all hope of the Tigers’ numerous chances. “Dartmouth played really well and they were very physical with us,” Head Coach Sean Driscoll told the ‘Prince.’ “I think they caught us a little bit off guard.” Throughout the half, Tordin was visibly frustrated, as every one of her touches on the ball was immediately swarmed by, at times, a three-to-one attack of the Dartmouth backline. In the second part of the half, Dartmouth began taking advantage of transitions and was able to slow the game down, something Princeton’s playing style is not used to. In the twentieth minute, Dartmouth forward Hannah Curtin hit a sharp cross into midfielder Aleena Seals, whose attempt was just beyond the goal. This followed a series of three set pieces that Princeton narrowly got away with as McCamey maintained her clean sheet. “The first half, we really didn’t play with the chip on our shoulder like we usually do,” MacNab said. “We are usually a very high pressing, aggressive team, and we were kind of on our heels. We also had the wind against us in the first half.” After a frustrating first half, Princeton returned to the field reinvigorated and with a stronger sense of identity. They pressed hard from the get go, driving down the field and possessing well in the final third — a shift from the lack of attack in the first half. On the second half press, MacNab explained, “We knew we had tired Dartmouth out a little bit, and we knew that as long as we had a really good ten minutes where we kept the ball and kept it in their half of the field, then we were going to be successful.” Their forward press quickly paid off in the 47th minute, when a foul on Princeton earned a free kick from the middle top of the box. Recent U.S. U-20 bronze medalist Pietra Tordin stepped up to the ball. “Honestly, that’s one of my favorite spots to hit a free kick from,” Tordin said. “Right before I kicked it, I was like, there’s a pretty good chance it’s gonna go in.” Tordin calmly approached the ball, taking three darting steps forward before blasting the ball with precise power into the net. This goal was one for the record books, as Tordin’s two goal game moved her from a tie for eleventh to tenth in program history for career goals, now standing with 26 career goals. Not even a minute and a half later, the Tigers added another mark to the scoresheet. Junior forward Drew Cumens received the ball in transition at the half and drove up the field. She took the ball up inside the right side of the box, touched around her defender, and then clinically slotted the ball past the diving arms of Dartmouth goalkeeper Emily Hardy and into the far-left-side netting. Princeton kept up the attack throughout the second half, generating lots of near chances. First-year forward Alexandra Barry, whose halftime substitution into the game helped to spark the team as she delivered two assists, had a specific mindset on Saturday. “Today is just a super special day,” Barry told the ‘Prince.’ “Our seniors on this team are just so special, and we all love them so much, so I just did everything I could in my power to get the win for my team.”  Get the best of the ‘Prince’ delivered straight to your inbox.   Subscribe now »  3/21/25, 6:20 PM   Women’s soccer downs Dartmouth 4–0 on senior day - The Princetonian  https://www.dailyprincetonian.com/article/2024/10/princeton-sports-recaps-womens-soccer-tigers-beat-dartmouth-big-green-senior-day   2/3</alto:String>
      </alto:TextBlock>
    </alto:Page>
  </alto:Layout>
</alto:alto>