<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alto:alto xmlns:alto="http://www.loc.gov/standards/alto/ns-v4#">
  <alto:Layout>
    <alto:Page ID="3">
      <alto:TextBlock>
        <alto:String>MF:   Oh, that’s a really hard question. I just went to a Kaytranada concert over the weekend, and he is such a fun performer to watch live, so I can’t even imagine how entertaining it would be to be blessed with sharing the board with him.  DP:   What is your process when putting together a set?  MF:   I’ve seen multiple different approaches. One of them is much more mathematical, and you time out all the bars so that you know the second the vocals begin of the new song. I take a less quantitative approach and have coded the stems of certain songs to correspond with the buns on my board. That means with one beat, with one touch of a button, I can turn on or off the bass, the vocals, the mids, whatever it is. I will typically mess around with the stems on the touchpad, as opposed to the EQs. I’m also trying to work on being less reliant on using the Serato-generated BPMs to help me determine the best follow up song. I also am one for wordplay, so I’m working on that. Love a good word play remix. My twin sister, who has perfect pitch, hates my general approach, because as long as the pitches aren’t complimentary, the entire mix is a wash to her.  DP:   Your DJ name is Disc Rocky. Can you tell me the story behind that?  MF:   Completely independent of my DJ hobby is my unpaid role as the Rocky mascot, Rocky the Squirrel. And I really need to stress that these are completely not associated with each other. Potentially an end goal would be to DJ in the squirrel suit for Rocky-sanctioned events. But until then, do know that my Disc Rocky name is both a play on “disc jockey” and the well known artist A$AP Rocky.  DP:   Do you see DJing in your long term plans?  MF:   I hope DJing will continue to be a fun release for me. It allows me to view the time I spend listening to music as efficient and productive, which is definitely the product of a Princeton mindset, but gives me a fun, fun hobby with progress that I can measure tangibly, which is totally up my alley as someone who likes to hone in on skills quickly and get good at them. That being said, I by no means see this as a career of mine. If really all else fails, at least I’ll know that at least I’ll be able to rely on my DJ and my mascot skills, right?  DP:   Two very valuable skills, honestly.  MF:   A professional mascot is well into the six figures, which is crazy. And I can do the splits but only in the squirrel costume.  DP:   Is there anything else you would like to add?  MF:   Definitely do contact me if you’re interested in pro and potentially pro bono DJ work. I know that I’m one of 1000 Princeton students in recent years to commit to a DJing hobby. But by extension, if anyone is interested in learning how to spin the discs themselves, I’m more than happy to offer up my board whenever, wherever, time and place. I’m there.  Annie Wang is an assistant editor for The Prospect from West Virginia. She can be reached at annie.wang[at]princeton.edu.  3/11/25, 12:15 AM   Artist Q&amp;A: Maddie Feldman’s DJ dreams as Disc Rocky - The Princetonian  https://www.dailyprincetonian.com/article/2024/10/princeton-prospect-artist-question-and-answer-disc-rocky-dj   3/3</alto:String>
      </alto:TextBlock>
    </alto:Page>
  </alto:Layout>
</alto:alto>