<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alto:alto xmlns:alto="http://www.loc.gov/standards/alto/ns-v4#">
  <alto:Layout>
    <alto:Page ID="page_18">
      <alto:TextBlock>
        <alto:String>While Princeton does not have an official statement on a preference for legacy applicants, a report by the   Ad Hoc Committee on Undergraduate Admission Policy   acknowledges a “limited preference” for children of alumni. The authors of the report note that legacy preference “recognizes the University’s special bond with its alumni” — indeed, over   25,000 alumni   attend Reunions each year. According to the report, legacy admissions “functions as a tiebreaker between equally well-qualified applicants in limited instances;” the authors concluded that the University should continue to practice legacy preference but “continue to carefully monitor [its] effects and implementation.” Through SCEA, Princeton admits applicants who have a clear preference for life in the Orange Bubble — and unsurprisingly, many of them claim Princeton heritage.  Hellen Luo is a contributing Data writer for The Daily Princetonian. Please send any corrections to corrections[at]dailyprincetonian.com.              SUBSCRIBE  News  U. Affairs Student Life Grad School Local Alumni  Q&amp;A Activism USG Research Academics Obituaries  Analysis Explainers  Opinion  Column Letter to the Editor Letter from the Editor Guest Submission Public Editor  Open Letter Reactions  Data  Surveys  Sports  News  Recaps Previews Profiles and Interviews  Features  Profiles  Retrospectives  Investigations  Visual Essays Cartoon Podcast  Daybreak  Brains, Black  Holes, and  Beyond  The Orange Table  The Prospect  Arts Entertainment  Lifestyle Self  Projects  Newsletter  Special Issues  Puzzles Humor  Masthead Contact Us Subscribe About Advertise Archives  Submit a Tip Donate  Privacy Terms  © 2025 The Daily Princetonian Powered by   Solutions by The State News  3/21/25, 6:20 PM   The Data Blog: 2028 Frosh Survey - The Princetonian  https://www.dailyprincetonian.com/article/2024/10/princeton-data-blog-frosh-survey-2028-results-analysis-chart-crosstab-longitudinal   9/9</alto:String>
      </alto:TextBlock>
    </alto:Page>
  </alto:Layout>
</alto:alto>