<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<alto:alto xmlns:alto="http://www.loc.gov/standards/alto/ns-v4#">
  <alto:Layout>
    <alto:Page ID="page_16">
      <alto:TextBlock>
        <alto:String>time to complete a structured program and 86 percent of students with incomes above $500k who took a gap year chose this option. As household income increased, the percentage of those who chose to work fell while the percentage of those chose to complete a structured program increased. The 2028 Frosh Survey shows the valuable opportunity that gap years provide for students to engage in a variety of experiences before entering Princeton. Whether through structured programs, work, or travel, students use this time to gain skills, explore interests, or prepare for the academic challenges ahead — though their preferences for activities during their gap year varied across socioeconomic status.  Hannah Choi is a contributing Data writer for the ‘Prince.’  Patterns in SCEA and legacy admissions, Oct. 2  Single-Choice Early Action (SCEA), a non-binding early admissions process prohibiting students from applying to other private institutions, has long been a distinctive feature of Princeton’s undergraduate admissions process. Among the Class of 2028 Frosh Survey respondents, 38.2 percent were admitted through SCEA. This continues the trend of students being admitted through SCEA, with the exception of the 2020–21 admissions cycle, when the University canceled the early admissions round due to   COVID-19 . Meanwhile, the number of students admitted to Princeton through the Questbridge National College Match program increased from 0.8 percent to 9.4 percent for the Class of 2025 and has remained just under 10 percent of the matriculating class since then. The University has   partnered   with Questbridge since 2006.  Other Institutions by Admission Type  Which of these other institutions, if any, offered you admission? Check all that apply.  Regular decision   Early action   QuestBridge   Waitlisted then accepted  n=566.  Created with   Datawrapper  20.0  40.0  60.0  80.0%  13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5% 13.5%  1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8%  11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3% 11.3%  21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1% 21.1%  7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6% 7.6%   11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0% 11.0%  2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8%  10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1% 10.1%  1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8%  38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8% 38.8%  9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5% 9.5%  1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8% 1.8%   2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8% 2.8%  14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7% 14.7%  9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8% 9.8%  Brown University  California Institute of Technology (Caltech)  Columbia University in the City of New York  Cornell University  Dartmouth College  Georgetown University  Harvard University  Johns Hopkins University  Massachusetts Institute of Technology  None of these schools offered me admission  Northwestern University  Stanford University  University of Chicago  University of Pennsylvania  Yale University  For the Class of 2028, only 21.4 percent of students admitted through SCEA gained acceptance from the other Ivy League schools and top institutions listed on the survey. In contrast, 61.2 percent of students admitted during the regular decision cycle and 76.9 percent of those accepted from the waitlist indicated that they were offered admission to other top institutions.  3/21/25, 6:20 PM   The Data Blog: 2028 Frosh Survey - The Princetonian  https://www.dailyprincetonian.com/article/2024/10/princeton-data-blog-frosh-survey-2028-results-analysis-chart-crosstab-longitudinal   7/9</alto:String>
      </alto:TextBlock>
    </alto:Page>
  </alto:Layout>
</alto:alto>