<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<alto xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/standards/alto/ns-v4#" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/alto/ns-v4# http://www.loc.gov/standards/alto/v4/alto-4-2.xsd" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <Description>
    <MeasurementUnit>pixel</MeasurementUnit>
    <sourceImageInformation>
      <fileName>page-0001.jp2</fileName>
    </sourceImageInformation>
  </Description>
  <Layout>
    <Page ID="page_1" PHYSICAL_IMG_NR="1" WIDTH="3400" HEIGHT="4400">
      <PrintSpace HPOS="0" VPOS="0" WIDTH="3400" HEIGHT="4400">
        <TextBlock ID="tb_1_1" HPOS="100" VPOS="100" WIDTH="3200" HEIGHT="200">
          <TextLine ID="tl_1_1" HPOS="110" VPOS="120" WIDTH="3180" HEIGHT="40" BASELINE="150">
            <String ID="str_1_1" CONTENT="Wednesday, April 26, 2023 Newsletter by Michelle Miao ** Music event brings up another debate about event sponsorship The Effron Music Building Angel Kuo / The Daily Princetonian Good morning! On April 12, the James Madison Program and the Department of Music co-sponsored the campus event, “Dvořák’s Prophecy and the Vexed Fate of Black Classical Music.” Guest contributor Peter Christian critiques the focus on white composers, arguing that given Princeton’s stature, it has a“responsibility to perpetuate offerings that align with its values and mission.” Christian voices opposition to the speakers and their handling of Black classical music. Christian says that the Department of Music’s collaboration with the James Madison Program was “concerning” and asks for greater awareness of the University’s choice to “uplift voices of white hypocrisy to the detriment of its proclaimed goals of diversity and inclusion.” This debate is a continuation, in more academic terms, of a larger debate about the choice of speakers and events by departments, which was most prominent when Palestinian writer Mohammed el-Kurd came to campus in February. Department and University officials highlighted different programs' right to host events and speakers of their choice, while Christian notes that attendees might perceive an institutional endorsement of the event. READ THE GUEST CONTRIBUTION→ Analysis by Olivia Chen ** Today’s Briefing: The evolution of mental health leaves at Princeton: The ‘Prince’ presents an overview of the past ten years of mental health-related leave of absences at Princeton. The findings show students’ satisfaction with the process has changed dramatically since the mid-2010s. While past cases included high profile negative experiences with the University’s mental health services, a Department of Justice review and University-wide changes have led two current students who spoke to the ‘Prince’ to report markedly better experiences. Justin Chae ’24, who took leave for a year, noted obtaining a mental health leave is a “very smooth process.” Princeton union members join in Rutgers strike: After a nine-day strike was suspended last week, contract negotiations continue between union members and administrators at Rutgers University (. While Princeton and Rutgers have historically rivaled, shared objectives between the universities’ unionized groups have now brought those calling for change together. Rutgers strikers’ demands included increased wages, race and gender equity, and the use of salary scales. According to Rebecca Givan, the president of an organizing union AAUP-AFT, the call is for “a better Rutgers.” Members of Princeton Graduate Students United PGSU) have been following the strike, and many joined those striking on the picket lines “to stand in solidarity with [their] academic neighbors.” Princeton High School walkout: Princeton High School (PHS) students walked out of afternoon classes on Friday, April 21, protesting the recent removal of Principal Frank Chmiel. His termination marks the fifth principal in the last four years. No explanation for his firing was offered. According to Elizabeth Semrod, a parent present at the walkout, Chmiel was “loved and adored by the students. I don’t know one parent or one student that’s not behind him.” The walkout drew over 75 students and parents who marched from PHS to the district building holding signs and shouting slogans that expressed their support for Chmiel. ProCES and LENS create service opportunities: The ‘Prince’ investigates how the University supports students’ engagement with service ( by examining two programs, ProCES (Program for Community-Engaged Scholarship) and LENS Learning and Education through Service), that are designed to expand students’ commitment to service in class and during the summer. Both offer programming that aim to increase student exposure to immersive learning and service through expanded resources and courses. ProCES involves a new format for courses, while LENS has rebranded existing opportunities for summer service under a new website and program. Jonathan Rosenberg ’25, who benefited from increased funding from the creation of LENS, told the ‘Prince:’ “I was able to choose an internship that I liked, as opposed to one that was simply the highest paying.” OPINION | The collapse of compact theory should mean statehood for Puerto Rico Whig Hall, where PDP held initiations in 2021 Angel Kuo / The Daily Princetonian Guest Contributor Ignacio Arias ’25 addresses the question of Puerto Rico statehood following a talk given by Eduardo Bhatia ’86, a visiting professor in the School of Public and International Affairs. Arias notes that while Bhatia addresses the politics of Puerto Rican identity, the “cultural question is often overstated.” Arias maintains that the main question for Puerto Rico is whether or not Congress is willing to grant statehood. One barrier to statehood is “compact theory,” which suggests that Puerto Rico became sovereign upon gaining Commonwealth status. Weighing statehood and independence, Arias writes: “Statehood is not the panacea to all of the island’s woes, but it will best equip Puerto Ricans to promote their interests and fully participate in national affairs.” READ THE GUEST CONTRIBUTION → MORE FROM OPINION: Ronen Shoval’s position as a lecturer at Princeton is deeply concerning: Princeton professors Eldar Shafir and Uri Hasson criticize the appointment of Ronen Shoval as a politics lecturer at the University. They point out Shoval’s history as a founder of an ultranationalist Israeli group that has “waged campaigns of intimidation and harassment against prominent human rights organizations, academic departments..., and scholars across Israel for years.” Shafir and Hasson emphasize that Shoval’s appointment to lecturer status is particularly concerning, as he “is now free to use his University affiliation to further advance his hateful agenda.” Shoval, invited to Princeton by the James Madison Foundation, is now teaching a freshman seminar at Princeton. “As faculty, we are embarrassed. We call on the University and its departments to reflect on who exactly we want to bring to teach our students,” Shafir and Hasson write. READ THE GUEST CONTRIBUTION → It’s time for Princeton to contextualize students’ GPAs: Assistant Opinion editor Henry Hsiao ’26 calls on the University to provide median grades for each course alongside students’ earned grades on their transcripts. Hsiao writes that these median grades would put a student’s performance in a class in the context of overall course performance. “ This method, also adopted at other colleges, will give a fuller account of a student’s academic circumstances, the nature of their coursework, and their relative successes, to clarify what may seem at times arbitrary and random,” he states. This proposal can protect against misinterpretations of student grades. Hsiao believes that this system will not only benefit students, but will also help faculty members adjust courses as needed, as well as give potential employers and graduate school admissions committees more information about student performance. READ THE COLUMN → ** At your leisure * CARTOON: The Daily Struggle by Contributing Cartoonist Aysu Turkay * DATA: The Data Blog: Unskewing average GPA * SPORTS: ‘Frustrated and exhausted’: The impact of concussions on Princeton student-athletes * PODCAST: Listen to the latest episode of Daybreak, The Daily Princetonian’s daily news podcast. If you have any feedback or concerns about today’s newsletter, please email managingeditor@dailyprincetonian.com Today’s newsletter was copy edited by Naisha Sylvestre and Bryan Zhang. Thank you. ** Twitter ** Facebook ** YouTube ** Instagram ** Email ** Spotify **" HPOS="110" VPOS="120" WIDTH="3180" HEIGHT="40"/>
          </TextLine>
        </TextBlock>
      </PrintSpace>
    </Page>
  </Layout>
</alto>